<resources>
    <string name="app_name">InfoApp</string>

    <!-- Languages Name -->
    <string name="lan1">C</string>
    <string name="lan2">C++</string>
    <string name="lan3">Java</string>
    <string name="lan4">Python</string>
    <string name="lan5">Kotlin</string>
    <string name="lan6">Swift</string>
    <string name="lan7">Rust</string>
    <string name="lan8">PHP</string>
    <string name="lan9">Java Script</string>
    <string name="lan10">Ruby</string>
    <string name="lan11">Type Script</string>
    <string name="lan12">Dart</string>
    <string name="lan13">Go</string>

    <!-- Info of languages -->
    <string name="info1">History of C language is interesting to know. Here we are going to discuss a brief history of the c language.
            C programming language was developed in 1972 by Dennis Ritchie at bell laboratories of AT and T (American Telephone and Telegraph),
            located in the U.S.A. Dennis Ritchie is known as the founder of the c language.It was developed to overcome the problems of previous
            languages such as B, BCPL, etc. Initially, C language was developed to be used in UNIX operating system.
            It inherits many features of previous languages such as B and BCPL.</string>
    <string name="info2">C++ was developed by Bjarne Stroustrup at Bell Laboratories over a period starting in 1979.
        Since C++ is an attempt to add object-oriented features (plus other improvements) to C, earlier it was called
        as “C with Objects”. As the language developed, Stroustrup named it as C++ in 1983. The name C++ suggests “C incremented”
        (recall the ++ is an increment operator of C).\nC++ was made available outside Bell Laboratories in 1985. The first commercial
        C++ compiler, Cfront, was released in 1985. It was only a front-end compiler for C. The American National
        Standard Institute (ANSI)
        formed a committee for (precise description of computer language) C++, in 1989. The first draft standards were published in 1995.
        The draft was modified later on. Revised draft was approved in 1998. Turbo C++ version 3.0 (from Borland International)
        was available in 1992.</string>
    <string name="info3">Java is a programming language and a platform. Java is a high level, robust, object-oriented and secure programming language.
        Java was developed by Sun Microsystems (which is now the subsidiary of Oracle) in the year 1995. James Gosling is known as the father of Java.
        Before Java, its name was Oak. Since Oak was already a registered company, so James Gosling and his team changed the name from Oak to Java.
        Platform: Any hardware or software environment in which a program runs, is known as a platform. Since Java has a runtime environment (JRE)
        and API, it is called a platform.</string>
    <string name="info4">Python is a widely used general-purpose, high-level programming language. It was initially designed by Guido van Rossum in
        1991 and developed by Python Software Foundation. It was mainly developed for emphasis on code readability, and its syntax allows
        programmers to express concepts in fewer lines of code. In the late 1980s, history was about to be written. It was that time when working 
        on Python started. Soon after that, Guido Van Rossum began doing its application based work in December of 
        1989 by at Centrum Wiskunde and Informatica (CWI) which is situated in Netherlands. It was started firstly as
        a hobby project because he was looking for an interesting project to 
        keep him occupied during Christmas. The programming language which Python is said to have succeeded is ABC Programming Language, which had the 
        interfacing with the Amoeba Operating System and had the feature of exception handling. He had already helped to create ABC earlier in his career
        and he had seen some issues with ABC but liked most of the features. After that what he did as really very clever. He had taken the syntax of
        ABC, and some of its good features. It came with a lot of complaints too, so he fixed those issues completely and had created a good scripting 
        language which had removed all the flaws. The inspiration for the name came from BBC\'s TV Show – ‘Monty Python\'s Flying Circus\', as he was a 
        big fan of the TV show and also he wanted a short, unique and slightly mysterious name for his invention and hence he named it Python! He was the
        “Benevolent dictator for life” (BDFL) until he stepped down from the position as the leader on 12th July 2018. For quite some time he used to work
        for Google, but currently, he is working at Dropbox. The language was finally released in 1991. When it was released, it used a lot fewer codes to
        express the concepts, when we compare it with Java, C++ and C. Its design philosophy was quite good too. Its
        main objective is to provide code
        readability and advanced developer productivity. When it was released it had more than enough capability to provide classes with inheritance, 
        several core data types exception handling and functions. </string>
    <string name="info5">Kotlin was developed by JetBrains in 2010. They initially released it under the name Project Kotlin in July 2011. They
        needed a language that was concise, elegant, expressive, and also interoperable with Java, as most of their products were
        developed in Java, including the Intellij Idea. They were looking for an alternate language to reduce the amount of boilerplate code required
        and to introduce new constructs, such as higher-order functions, to make language more expressive and concise. One of the goals of the Kotlin
        language was to be able to compile code as quickly as Java.</string>
    <string name="info6">Swift was introduced in 2014 at Apples\'s Worldwide Developers Conference.
        The development of Swift was started in 2010 by Chris Lattner with other programmers i.e. Doug Gregor, John McCall, Ted Kremenek, and Joe Groff
        at Apple. The basic idea of Swift was taken from Objective-C, Rust, Haskell, Ruby, Python, C#, CLU, and many other programming languages.
        Swift first version was 1.0 which undergone a major upgrade to Swift 2 at WWDC 2015. Its upgraded version 2.2 was made open-source software under
        the Apache License 2.0 on December 3, 2015, for Apple\'s platforms and Linux.
        Its third version, Swift 3.0 went through a significant evolution where its syntax was changed. Swift overcame the popularity of Objective
        C in the first quarter of 2018.</string>
    <string name="info7">The Rust programming language first debuted in 2010. Despite its relative youth, however, the language has quickly gained
        in popularity, offering a combination of performance and features that make it an appealing alternative to
        traditional options. Rust began as a side project of Graydon Hoare, an employee at Mozilla. In short order, Mozilla saw the potential of the
        new language and began sponsoring it, before revealing it to the world in 2010.
        One possible source of the name, according to Hoare, is the rust fungus. This has caused Rust programmers to adopt “Rustceans” as their moniker of
        choice. While Rust is relatively new, it has obviously gained a strong following. In relation to the languages it is compared against, especially
        C and
        C++, Rust is easier to learn and safer to use for new programmers.</string>
    <string name="info8">PHP was conceived sometime in the fall of 1994 by Rasmus Lerdorf. Early non-released versions were used on his home page to keep
        track of who was looking at his online resume. The first version used by others was available sometime in early 1995 and was known as the
        Personal Home Page Tools. It consisted of a very simplistic parser engine that only understood a few special macros and a number of
        utilities that were in common use on home pages back then. A guestbook, a counter and some other stuff. The parser was rewritten in mid-1995
        and named PHP/FI Version 2. The FI came from another package Rasmus had written which interpreted html form data. He combined the Personal Home
        Page tools scripts with the Form Interpreter and added mSQL support and PHP/FI was born. PHP/FI grew at an amazing pace and people started
        contributing code
        to it. It is difficult to give any hard statistics, but it is estimated that by late 1996 PHP/FI was in use on at least 15,000 web sites around
        the world. By mid-1997 this number had grown to over 50,000. Mid-1997 also saw a change in the development of PHP. It changed from being Rasmus\'
        own pet project that a handful of people had contributed to, to being a much more organized team effort. The parser was rewritten from scratch by
        Zeev Suraski and Andi Gutmans and this new parser formed the basis for PHP Version 3. A lot of the utility code from PHP/FI was ported over to PHP3
        and a lot of it was completely rewritten.</string>
    <string name="info9">JavaScript is everywhere, and for the seventh year in a row, it has been ranked the most commonly used programming language,
        with 67.8% of developers employing it in 2019. Its ascent to the world\'s most popular programming language is synonymous with the rise of
        the internet itself. Created out of necessity, it is used to build 95.2% (1.52 billion) of websites today, including some of the world\'s largest
        , like Facebook and YouTube. Without it, we would not have popular and useful web apps such as Google Maps and eBay. JavaScript is a scripting
        language that is one of the three core languages used to develop websites. Whereas HTML and CSS give a website structure and style, JavaScript lets
        you add functionality and behaviors to your website, allowing your website\'s visitors to interact with content in many imaginative ways.
        JavaScript is primarily a client-side language, meaning it runs on your computer within your browser. However, more recently the introduction
        of Node.js has allowed JavaScript to also execute code on servers.
        Since its release, JavaScript has surpassed Java, Flash, and other languages because it is relatively easy to learn, has a free and open community,
        and, most importantly, is incredibly useful, allowing developers to quickly create apps with audiences in the millions.</string>
    <string name="info10">Ruby was created by Yukihiro Matsumoto, or "Matz", in Japan in the mid 1990\'s. It was
        designed for programmer productivity with the idea that programming should be fun for programmers. It emphasizes the necessity for software
        to be understood by humans first and computers second. Ruby continues to gain popularity for its use in web application development. The Ruby on Rails framework, built with the Ruby
        language by David Heinemeier Hansson, introduced many people to the joys of programming in Ruby. Ruby has a vibrant community that is supportive
        for beginners and enthusiastic about producing high-quality code.</string>
    <string name="info11">TypeScript programming language was designed and developed by Anders Hejlsberg at Microsoft
        in the year 2012. TypeScript programming language is now maintained by Microsoft. The first version of
        TypeScript programming language i.e. version 0.8 was publically introduced in October, 2012. And the lastest version of TypeScript programming
        language i.e. version 4.2.4 was officially released on 9 April 2021. TypeScript programming language is an extended version of JavaScript
        programming language with some added features. TypeScript programming language is an open source programming language since its origin and it
        was licensed under Apache 2.0 license. TypeScript programming language is a superset of JavaScript programming language or in simple words
        TypeScript programming language is an extended JavaScript with added features. TypeScript programming language is considered as both Computer
        programming language and set of tools. It is a simple, easy to learn and fast programming language. TypeScript programming language is an open
        source programming language since its origin which means that anyone can download and use it for free from its official website and it was
        licensed under Apache 2.0 license.
        TypeScript programming language supports multi paradigm like imperative, functional, generic and object oriented. TypeScript programming
        language is considered as object oriented programming language as it follows all the concepts of object oriented programming approach like class
        , inheritance, abstraction, polymorphism and encapsulation, etc. TypeScript programming language is portable programming language which is
        designed to develop large JavaScript applications and transpiler to JavaScript programming language.
        TypeScript programming language is also used to develop both client server and side server applications of JavaScript programming language.
        TypeScript programming language is a complied programming language whose codes are complied into plain JavaScript programming language. Along with
        this, TypeScript programming language supports different typing disciplines like duck, gradual and structural. TypeScript programming language
        also supports the feature of error checking during compilation. And apart from this, TypeScript programming language also supports different
        libraries and elements of JavaScript programming language. The idea of developing TypeScript programming language was taken from many other
        programming languages like Java, JavaScript and C#.</string>
    <string name="info12">Dart is a modern, class based and easy to learn programming language. Dart programming language is originally designed
        as a client optimised programming language for fast development of web and mobile applications. Dart programming language is an open
        source programming language which is licensed under BDS. It is a programming language which supports multi paradigm like imperative,
        functional, reflective and Object oriented programming. Dart programming language follows all concepts of object oriented programming approach
        like class, inheritance, abstraction, encapsulation, and polymorphism, etc. Dart programming language is a strongly typed which provides
        the feature of automatic garbage collector.
        The syntax of Dart programming language are simple C-style syntax. Dart programming language is a multi purpose or general purpose 
        programming language which means that it can be used in developing different types of applications and programs. The Dart programming language
        is mainly used in developing web applications, mobile applications, desktop applications, servers, etc. Dart programming language is a cross
        platform or platform independent programming language which means that it can be run on different operating systems like Windows, Linux, Unix and
        MacOS, etc.
        Dart programming language was influenced by many other programming languages like Java, C# and JavaScript. Dart programming language is a
        complied programming language which means that compiler is used to convert the codes written in Dart programming language into native language
        or JavaScript. You all must be curious about the history of Dart programming language or wondering who developed Dart programming language.
        There are various interesting facts related to the origin of Dart programming language. So, let\'s discuss in detail about the history of Dart
        programming language. Dart programming language was designed and developed by Lars Bak and Kasper Lund at Google.
        Dart programming language was officially introduced in 10 Oct, 2011 and the first version of Dart programming language i.e. version 1.0 was
        officially released in 14 Nov, 2013. The latest version of Dart programming language is version 2.13.0 which is released in 18 May, 2021.</string>
    <string name="info13">The story of the Go programming language started at Google, when three engineers, Robert Griesemer, Rob Pike, and Ken
        Thompson grew weary of C++\'s complexity, and the lack of a simple language providing efficient compilation and execution. That\'s why on September
        21, 2007, they started designing a new language. It took them two years before, on November 10, 2009, the Go programming language became a
        public open source project. After three more years, in March 2012, version 1.0 of the Go language was released.
        The Go inventors\' main goal was to combine the ease of programming from an interpreted, dynamically-typed language with the efficiency
        and safety coming from a statically-typed, compiled language. Moreover, the Go language was intended to support network and multicore computing,
        and to accelerate the coding process.
        To achieve these goals, Griesemer, Pike, and Thompson focused on simplicity. That\'s why the Go language\'s syntax is inspired by the C family.
        Other input, e.g. from Pascal, you can notice in the declarations and packages. The other inspirations were Newsqueak and Limbo - they helped
        create the concurrency aspect of Go. That makes this programming language a mix of the best features of these various solutions. </string>
</resources>